skybingo.com 2017-03-12

# Cookies Policy & Privacy Notice – Help - Sky Bingo

###### Cookies Policy

This cookies policy (the “Policy”) applies to the websites operated by each of Bonne Terre Limited and Hestview Limited, whose trading names include Sky Betting & Gaming, Sky Bet, Sky Vegas, Sky Casino, Sky Bingo, Sky Poker, Fantasy Six-A-Side, Sky Sports Super 6, Sky Sports Fantasy Football and Sportinglife (collectively, “Sky Betting & Gaming” or “SB&G”) and are a part of the Sky Betting & Gaming group of companies ('Sky B&G Group').

When you create or log into an online account via the Sky Betting & Gaming websites, you agree to our use of cookies as set out in this Policy. Otherwise, by continuing to scroll, click, navigate or use the Sky Betting & Gaming websites, content, products or services you agree to the use of cookies as described in this Policy.

You should be aware that when you access or use our content, products and services, we may collect information from your devices by using 'cookies'. For further details about the types of cookies we use, please see the section “Cookies on the Sky Betting & Gaming websites” below.

If you would like to learn more about your cookie settings, how to manage these cookies and/or how to opt-out from the cookies being set, please see the section "Controlling My Cookies" below.

#### What are cookies and how do they work?

Cookies are small bits of text and numbers that are downloaded onto the devices you use to receive Sky Betting & Gaming content, products and services and access online information. Your browser makes these cookies available every time you visit the website again, so it can recognise you and your device and can then tailor what you see.

#### What do we use cookies for?

Cookies play an important part in the day-to-day functioning of websites and other online content. Cookies help your device or browser to access information (for example, the selections you have placed in your bet slip), identify you as a user (for example, so we can keep you logged into your account when you navigate around the websites) or use certain features (for example, you want to reset your PIN or User ID) when you use the Sky Betting and Gaming websites. We also sometimes use other cookies to help prevent fraud (for example, by detecting multiple fraudulent transactions from the same computer) or to enhance your experience (for example, by showing more relevant price boosts based on your previous activity). We do not use cookies for any reason that does not:

  * Make adverts and other content more effective and relevant to you.
  * Ensure we can pay our affiliate partners correctly for the users they refer to us.
  * Improve your Sky Betting and Gaming experience by providing anonymised analytics.
  * Deliver features and content (for example we might want to see how many customers visited the homepage yesterday compared to last week).
  * Detect and defend against fraud and other security risks to protect our customers, partners and Sky Betting and Gaming itself.
  * Meet our legal, compliance and regulatory duties. SB&G are regulated by both the Alderney Gambling Control Commission and United Kingdom Gambling Commission.
  * Continually improve our products and services (for example, by testing different product experiences with different users to see which the best is).

As outlined in the summary above, there are many different types of, and uses for, cookies. However, they can be grouped in the following four main groups: (1) strictly necessary, (2) functionality, (3) targeting and (4) analytical. Further detail about how and why Sky Betting and Gaming uses each of this type of cookie can be found in the detail below:

###### Cookies on the Sky Betting & Gaming websites

Our websites use the following cookies:

**Type of Cookie:** Strictly necessary - some are session and persistent cookies. Some of these cookies are set by third parties such as OpenBet, Omniture, RaceCaller and GFM.  
**What do they do?** These are cookies which are needed to provide the content, product or service you have asked for. These cookies are essential to help your device download or stream information, so that you can move around our websites and use their features. Without these cookies, we can’t provide the content, products or services you've asked for.  
**How do we use this type of cookie?** Here are a few examples of the ways in which we use strictly necessary cookies:  

  * positioning information on your smartphone screen, tablet device or other screen so that you can see and use our websites;
  * keeping you logged in during your visit so that you don’t have to log in on every one of our websites each time you visit;
  * enabling you to stream content, without having to repeatedly adjust your volume and viewing settings; and
  * allowing you to navigate through our websites smoothly by identifying your device or browser and subsequently showing the most appropriate format of website.

**Do these cookies collect my personal data? Does the information get passed onto third parties?** Yes, some of these cookies do collect your personal data and some of your personal data may be passed onto third parties such as RaceCaller and GFM.  
**Links to more information** Page 8 – 9 of this guide, provided by the ICO, details the types of cookies in more detail: <https://www.cookielaw.org/media/1096/icc_uk_cookiesguide_revnov.pdf>

**Type of Cookie:** Functionality. Some of these cookies are set by third parties such as Maxymiser, OpenBet, and GetClicky.  
**What do they do?** These cookies recognise you when you return to our website and allow us to remember the choices you make. They also help us to provide improved features.  
**How do we use this type of cookie?** Here are a few examples of some of the ways in which we use functionality cookies:  

  * remembering your preferences and settings, including language, location and marketing preferences (such as choosing whether you wish to receive marketing information);
  * remembering the selections in your betslip;
  * remembering if you've used a specific application or website before;
  * showing you information that's relevant to the content, products or services that you receive;
  * giving you access to content provided by social-media websites, such as Twitter; and
  * showing 'related article' links that are relevant to the information you're looking at.

**Do these cookies collect my personal data? Does the information get passed onto third parties?** Yes, some of these cookies do collect your personal data. Some of these cookies don't collect personal data, but we do sometimes pass on this anonymised data to third parties such as Maxymiser.  
**Links to more information** Page 8 – 9 of this guide, provided by the ICO, details the types of cookies in more detail: <https://www.cookielaw.org/media/1096/icc_uk_cookiesguide_revnov.pdf>

**Type of Cookie:** Targeting. Some of these cookies are set by third parties such as TeaLeaf, Revenue Science, Google and Oddschecker.  
**What do they do?** We sell space on some of our websites to advertisers. The resulting adverts often contain cookies which are stored onto your device as you visit different websites. The advertiser uses the browsing information collected from these cookies to:  

  * restrict the number of times you are shown a particular advertisement. This is sometimes called 'frequency capping'; and
  * show other advertisements that are relevant to you, while you're accessing our information.

Your browsing activity may be grouped with information about what is being accessed by other users within similar interest and demographic groups. The result is then used to show you advertisements based on those interests. This is often called online behavioral advertising (OBA).  
**How do we use this type of cookie?** Here are a few examples of some of the ways in which we use targeting cookies:

  * to remember websites you have visited;
  * to remember links you have followed; and
  * within advertisements for our own Sky Betting & Gaming products.

We use a cookie placed by a company called Lotame to collect non-personal data that is used for OBA purposes. To opt-out of the collection and use of data by Lotame for OBA on your browser (including a mobile browser if third-party cookies are enabled in your browser), you can click [here](http://www.lotame.com/opt-out-preference-manager/) and follow the instructions provided. Your opt-out choice is applied only to the browser from which you make the choice. Note that our opt-out is cookie based, and so if you delete your cookies, you may no longer be opted out and you may need to opt-out again  
We use targeting cookies to make our website and advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests.  
**Do these cookies collect my personal data? Does the information get passed onto third parties?** Yes, some of these cookies do collect your personal data.  
**Links to more information** Page 8 – 9 of this guide, provided by the ICO, details the types of cookies in more detail: <https://www.cookielaw.org/media/1096/icc_uk_cookiesguide_revnov.pdf>

**Type of Cookie:** Analytical. Some of these cookies are set by third parties such as Omniture, and Google.  
**What do they do?** Analytical cookies gather information about which of our websites, information and links are popular and which ones don't get used as much. Our applications, web locations, websites and communications that you get from us also contain small invisible images known as 'web beacons' or 'pixels'. These ‘pixels’ simply let us know that an advert or affiliate partner has successfully connected a customer to SB&G. For example, when a new customer successfully registers on a SB&G website after clicking an advert, a “pixel” will let us know that the advert worked or that we need to pay an affiliate partner for sending a new customer to us. These pixels cannot identify an individual user.  
Your information is collected and grouped together with information collected from everyone else’s devices. We can then see overall patterns of usage, rather than any one person’s activity.  
**How do we use this type of cookie?** Here are a few examples of some of the ways in which we use Analytical cookies:  

  * to identify trends about how people navigate (find their way through) our information and when and where 'error messages' may originate;
  * to help us keep our information relevant and up to date;
  * to count the number of times a page or email has been viewed and allow us to measure the effectiveness of the communication; and
  * to improve how our applications, and websites and their pages work.

**Do these cookies collect my personal data? Does the information get passed onto third parties?** Yes, some of these cookies collect some personal data. We pass on both anonymised and personal information collected onto third parties such as Omniture and Google  
**Links to more information** Page 8 – 9 of this guide, provided by the ICO, details the types of cookies in more detail: <https://www.cookielaw.org/media/1096/icc_uk_cookiesguide_revnov.pdf>

**Type of Cookie:** iesnare  
**What do they do?** We use the iesnare cookie to prevent fraud and protect customers.  
**How do we use this type of cookie?** We use the iesnare cookie:  

  * to prevent money laundering;
  * to verify customer identity and financial details; and
  * to prevent fraudulent transactions.

**Do these cookies collect my personal data? Does the information get passed onto third parties?** The iesnare cookie collects your IP address along with certain device information. We pass information captured by the iesnare cookie (for example your device's IP address), onto Iovation (a third party organisation) as part of our efforts to ensure that customers are genuine, have not registered more than once or are not fraudulently trying to access accounts that do not belong to them. 

#### Cookies explained

Neither we, nor the companies who show advertisements on our websites, sell personal data collected from cookies to any other organisations. Where we transfer any of your data to third parties, we do so in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

It is easy for you to choose not to receive behavioural advertising and manage your cookie preferences. Please see the "Controlling my Cookies" section below for further details.

#### Controlling my Cookies

**How can I see and manage my cookies in my browser?**  
Virtually all modern browsers allow you to see what cookies you have, and to clear them individually or in their entirety. To find out how to do this, visit [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/), which contains comprehensive information about how to manage your cookie preferences on a wide variety of desktop browsers.

**How can I choose not to receive Online Behavioural Advertising and other tracking cookies?**  
In addition to the controls available on your computer and through the Sky Betting & Gaming websites, there are other ways of choosing not to receive Online Behavioural Advertising and other tracking cookies.

Please note that most of these choices work by setting a cookie that remembers your choice of opting-out. If you clear all of your cookies, you will also clear these opt-out cookies. In this instance you would need to opt-out from Online Behavioural Advertising again.

The following organisations provide more information about Online Behavioural Advertising:

  * [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/) \- This allows you to choose not to receive behavioural advertising from the majority of the advertising networks.
  * [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)](https://www.networkadvertising.org/) – Please see the “opt-out” page. This allows you to opt-out of behavioural advertising from each of the ad networks represented by the NAI.
  * [European Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.edaa.eu/) – Please see the Online Behavioural Advertising choices page.

**Can I disable cookies altogether rather than just deleting them?**  
Yes. If you would rather not let websites set any cookies at all on your browser or device you can follow the steps outlined below. Please note that this will affect the normal function of Sky Betting and Gaming websites and other websites that you might access.

**Internet Explorer**  
To prevent new cookies from being installed and delete existing cookies: <http://windows.microsoft.com/en-GB/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies>

**Firefox**  
To prevent new cookies from being installed: <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>  
To delete existing cookies: <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored>

**Google Chrome**  
To prevent new cookies from being installed and delete existing cookies: <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en>

**Safari**  
To prevent new cookies from being installed and delete existing cookies: <http://help.apple.com/safari/mac/8.0/#/sfri11471>

**How can I get more information?**  
Any queries or comments about this Policy should be sent to [support@skybet.com](mailto:support@skybet.com) with the subject line “Cookie Policy Query”.

This Cookies Policy was last updated on 23 May 2016.

###### Privacy Policy

This privacy notice applies to the use of personal information and other information by each of Bonne Terre Limited and Hestview Limited, whose trading names include Sky Betting & Gaming, Sky Bet, Sky Vegas, Sky Casino, Sky Bingo, Sky Poker, Sky Games, Sky Sports Super 6, Sky Sports Fantasy Football and Sportinglife (collectively, **'Sky Betting & Gaming'**) and are a part of the Sky Betting & Gaming group of companies ( **'Sky B &G Group'**).

Any member of the Sky B&G Group may use and share, within that group and with its advisors, the information you provide and other information it holds about you for the purposes set out below.

#### Information we may hold

  * Information you provided to us, including on our websites
  * Information about our content, products and services you’ve interacted with or played including without limitation by way of making deposits, bets or wagers in relation to any of Sky Betting & Gaming’s services.
  * Information provided by other companies who’ve obtained your permission to share information about you.
  * Information, uploads and comments you make about the services you use and our related products including any Sky Poker programmes, including how you access, view, share, contribute to and communicate with them.
  * Information we collect from devices you use to receive Sky Betting & Gaming content, products and services and about your use of Sky Betting & Gaming and/or selected third party content, products and services. For more information about cookies and how to manage them please see the Cookies Notice below.
  * IP address (this is a number that identifies a specific network device on the internet and is required for your device to communicate with websites) and location data.
  * Technical information from the devices you use to receive Sky Betting & Gaming content, products and services, for example the collection of diagnostic and traffic information.

#### How we may use your information

In addition to using your information to provide you with content, products, services, tailored and personalised recommendations and general account management, we may also use your information in the following ways:

  1. To monitor, improve and protect our content, products and services, work with our agents and business partners to improve the products and services we offer, and develop new content, products and services.
  2. We may share information with credit reference, fraud prevention agencies and other companies for use in credit decisions, for fraud detection, prevention and debt recovery purposes.
  3. We may transfer your information to our data processors outside the European Economic Area, but will do so with appropriate measures and controls in place to protect that information in accordance with applicable data protection laws and regulations.
  4. If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, the details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies. Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information. We and other organisations may also access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example when: checking details on applications for credit and credit related or other facilities; managing credit and credit related accounts and facilities; recovering debt; checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance; or checking details of job applications and employees. We and other organisations may access and use from other countries the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies. Please contact us using information on the Help & Support pages on www.skybet.com for more information.
  5. For market research.
  6. To enable us to comply with any legal or regulatory requirements; to protect or enforce our rights or the rights of any third party; in the detection and prevention of fraud and other crimes; and for the purpose of safeguarding national security.
  7. We may disclose your information to any successors of our business for them to use for the purposes set out in this Privacy Notice.
  8. If you log into one of our products through Facebook, Facebook provides us with some of your Facebook user details. We may use and share these details with our partners, each of whom may use the details to provide you with a more personalised experience on Facebook. This means that we and they may, for example, tailor the advertisements you see on Facebook so that you see advertisements for similar apps to Apps provided by us.

**Unless you've asked us not to:**

  9. To send you periodic communications and other information about your chosen content, products and services.
  10. To send you direct marketing from us or our trusted business partners (specifically including Sky UK Ltd). This may include communications by post, telephone or email and SMS, about us and our business partners’ content, products and services, events and special offers, including, where applicable, for a reasonable time after you have ceased to be a customer of ours.
  11. To provide you with tailored advertising. This means that we have your agreement to use the information we hold about you, for example, to make some of the adverts you see more relevant to you. 

###### Your preferences

#### Marketing

  12. You can choose not to receive direct marketing. You can adjust your preferences in the following ways:
  13. via your Sky Betting & Gaming, Sky Games, Super 6 or Fantasy Football account, as applicable.
  14. by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link in email marketing information from us in relation to future email marketing.
  15. by replying "STOP" to 57785 in any SMS message in relation to future SMS messages. 

#### Online behavioural advertising

  16. If you don't want any information processed through the use of cookies, please see the Cookies Notice below. 

#### Contacting Sky Betting & Gaming

  17. Any queries or comments about this Privacy Notice or for requests of copies of the information we hold about you should be sent to support@skybet.com with the subject line “Data Protection Query”.
  18. Please ensure you notify us of any updates, amendments and corrections to your information by contacting us using information on the Help & Support pages on www.skybet.com or by phoning us on 0330 024 4777 (or +44 (0) 1133 8876449 if calling form overseas) or writing to Sky Betting & Gaming, 2 Wellington Place, Leeds, West Yorkshire, LS1 4AP.

We may make changes to this Privacy Notice at any time, at our sole discretion. Such changes will take effect from the date specified by us on our websites, whether or not we have notified you specifically of such changes. It is important, therefore, that You log in to the websites from time to time to check to see whether there is a notification of change.

You agree to be solely responsible for becoming informed of such changes. If You continue to use the Sky Betting & Gaming websites or services after the effective date of certain changes (regardless of the way we have notified such changes), You agree to be bound by those changes whether or not You have had actual notice of, or have read, the relevant changes. If You do not agree to be bound by relevant changes, You should not continue to use our websites or services any further.

This Privacy Notice was last updated on 19th March 2015.
